

# Mohamed S. Elshamy

- mselshamy001@gmail.com
- https://www.LinkedIn.com/in/msvisiong/
- https://www.behance.net/msvisiong/
- (a) +20 101 231 6040

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- AutoCAD
- Revit
- 3Ds Max
- V-Rav renderer
- Corona renderer
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Sketchup
- Fusion360
- Grasshopper
- Phython
- Blender
- 7Brush
- MS Excel

#### **SUMMARY**

"Versatile, bilingual and motivated architectural designer, interior designer and technical office engineer with over seven years of experience in schematic design and technical drawings of projects ranging in size from small private projects to full scale multi-million dollar high profile corporate construction projects."

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Pre Master's (Sustainable Building Technology) 2013 - 2014

Ain Shams University Cairo, Egypt

#### B.Sc. (Architectural Engineering) 2006 - 2012

2004 - 2006

2017 - Current

Higher Institute of Engineering and Technology Kafr Elsheikh, Egypt

### High school (Mathematics)

Experimental Language Schools Kafr Elsheikh, Egypt

# COURSES & WORKSHOPS

- Design Summer School 2020
- The Architecture Summit Egypt 2020
- Phython programming language & Data Science (mimo)
- Sustainable Building Design (edX)
- Design Thinking and Creativity for Innovation (edX)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### El Soadaa Group

**Technical Office Engineer** 

Working on The Ministries District project at The New Administrative Capital.

- Developing and preparing shop drawings from design, construction drawings, engineering calculations, specification sheets and other data for approval.
- Coordinating, resolving construction conflicts, requesting clarification from the consultant for approval.
- Giving technical advice to the project team, and providing additional support with a wide variety of tools.
- Preparing with approved manufacturers all necessary documents for submitting of shop drawings.

### **LANGUAGES**

#### Arabic

Native speaker

#### **English**

 Equivalent to: CEFR C1, IELTS 7.0

# SOFT SKILLS

- Problem-Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Flexibility
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Organization
- Creativity
- Attention to Detail
- Responsibility
- Emotional
  Intelligence

#### **INTERESTS**

- Product design
- Graphic design
- Architecture and landscape photography
- Concept art
- Video games
- 3D art and motion graphics
- Programming and AI
- Scientific achievements

# WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Freelancing

2016 - 2017

self-employed

- Consulted with potential clients about project details and negotiate compensation.
- Communicated through presentation and meetings with foreign clients and government agencies about design specifications.
- Prepared preliminary sketches, layouts, and drawings for personal clients.
- Produced designs both for commercial enterprise and residential living.
- Rendered plans and 3D models of many project with the highest quality.

#### Aldewan for Constructions and Consultants

2015 - 2016

Architectural Technician

- Developed construction drawings of
  The University Emergency Hospital at Tanta University.
- Designed residential, commercial, office and hospitality projects.
- Creatively produced 2D & 3D rendering for exteriors, interior spaces, and landscapes.

## **ERA Culture Design**

2013 - 2015

Junior Interior designer

- Produced high quality 3D renderings of a wide range of interior and exterior spaces.
- Developed detailed plans and 3D models showing arrangement of walls, dividers, finishes, displays, lighting and other fixtures using CAD software and graphics software.
- Developed plans, elevations, cross sections and detailed drawings, and advised on selection of colors, materials, interior lighting, furniture and other items, taking into account ergonomic and occupational health standards.
- Modeled and developed 3D printed award wining furniture prototypes.
- Supervised projects to assist in the construction progress and insuring the highest quality.

#### **Alahram Consultants**

2012 - 2013

Trainee Architect

- Designed many residential and commercial projects.
- Rendered architectural plans and facades using industry standard visualization tools.
- Produced 3D renderings and presentations of many projects for the clients' proposals.